[♪ opening theme song playing]
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[traffic passing]
♪
Danji, no more lies.
You're not a human, are you?
-[Danji breathes shakily]
-[YURU] You're a daemon.
All this time,
you've lied to me, too.
[DANJI]
And this is my true form.
[Ken gasps]
A little boy and girl,
Zashiki-Warashi.
[YURU] Kyoka too?
Was everyone lying?
That's it.
There's not a soul
in the village I can trust.
They all want me dead.
[inhales]
[sighs]
[dog panting]
[Yuru grunts]
What do you want?
[yelps]
Hey, could you leave?
I've got a lot on my mind,
and I'd kinda like
some time alone!
[dog continues panting]
Damn mutt won't go.
Hmm.
There's always too much going on
in the world down here.
I can't get a moment's solitude.
Back in the village,
I could go into the mountains
to be alone.
I could think freely
without any interruptions.
Between the bandits,
beasts, and nature itself,
the threat of death
is ever present
in the mountains.
That made things simple.
Just focus on survival.
What do I need to do
in this moment
to be alive the next?
If I could focus on that,
all the noise in my mind
would go away
and I could find answers.
That's why I love the mountains.
But there he was. Danji.
Always wanting
to tag along with me.
He'd say,
"What if something bad happens
to you while you're alone?"
[grunts softly]
It was so annoying.
EPISODE 15
YURU AND DANJI
[bird screeching]
[Yuru (child) cries]
[YURU (CHILD)]
Mom and Dad fled the village.
Now Asa and I are all alone.
I can't believe it.
They're really gone.
[continues crying]
Well, I'm not.
Now and forever,
I'll stay by your side.
[Yuru grunts]
Damn.
I wasn't trying
to think about that,
so why'd you
have to remind me?
[dog panting]
He told us he didn't want
anyone else there.
[FEMALE DAEMON]
A dog isn't a person.
So this doesn't count.
♪
[LEFT] 'Tis apparent
why you've taken
such a liking to your master.
[female daemon chuckles]
We're all the same.
[gasps] You're getting
a little too friendly.
[FEMALE DAEMON]
None of us can live alone.
[footsteps]
[YURU] Where's Danji?
The young lad just ran off
by himself.
[MALE DAEMON]
Welcome back, Master.
[RIGHT]
He said he had something to do.
[YURU] What's that?
[LEFT] He appears to have sensed
his other half here
in the outside world.
Wait, you mean the fake Asa?
Did she also come down
the mountain?
He went off to look for her.
[YURU] By himself?
But how?
[RIGHT] We daemons have
a strong bond
with our other half.
He'll find his way.
[LEFT]
Even from great distances,
we can divine
each other's location.
Still, come on.
He left without saying goodbye.
I had questions I wanted
to ask him.
[KEN] He gave me
a message for you.
He said sorry,
and that he wouldn't be making
any excuses.
[YURU] Hm?
-[grunts]
-[dog pants]
[FEMALE AND MALE DAEMON]
Mm. Mm-hm.
[MALE DAEMON]
The sun is starting to go down,
so we should leave
before it gets too dark outside.
Aye, so long.
[FEMALE DAEMON] We like
hanging out around this area.
Feel free to contact us anytime.
Great, thank you! [chuckles]
It's so nice talking to daemons
who don't want to eat me!
[all grunt]
[FEMALE DAEMON] Mr. Danji.
[MALE DAEMON] You're looking
for your other half, right?
-Let us help.
-Oh, no,
I would hate for you
to go to any trouble for me.
[FEMALE DAEMON]
It's no trouble.
[MALE DAEMON] We spend
a lot of time around here,
so we know the area.
If we put our talents together,
we're sure to find them
before long.
Besides...
[FEMALE DAEMON]
We love to make friends
with even more living legends
like yourself.
[MALE DAEMON]
You're a Zashiki-Warashi!
That's, like, a celeb!
[FEMALE DAEMON]
Where shall we start?
[MALE DAEMON]
We'll show you the way.
[Danji (tsugai) cries]
[MALE DAEMON] Oh, no!
What's going on?
Why are you crying?
What happened?
[overlapping chatter]
[horse neighs]
What's going on?
Did I miss the invite?
[HANA] Oh, hey, Dera.
Welcome back.
Wow. You had a beard
last time we met, didn't you?
Hello, Oshirasama.
What brings you to our home?
I took the highway.
I didn't mean
what literally brought you.
And horses are considered
motorless vehicles,
so they aren't allowed
to be on highways.
My goodness!
We broke traffic laws!
[DERA] Hmm? What?
You finished the hot pot
without me!
-[cries]
-Thank you for the meal.
Why, Yuru!
Didn't you say we'd eat
together as a family?
Well, Hana told me.
There's no way for us to know
when an emergency
is gonna strike,
so you always need to eat
whenever you get the chance to.
Plus, it was gonna spoil.
Thank you for the meal.
Seemed like good logic to me.
Yeah?
Yeah, you do make a good point.
I should've eaten the hot pot
while I had the chance.
[HANA] Did you not get anything
while you were out?
[DERA] I was planning to grab
a bite at Jin's place,
but they only served me
canned coffee.
Here. From Jin.
Asked me to give it to you.
[Yuru gasps]
It's that magic painting
of my mom and dad!
[RIGHT] Oh?
[YURU] She told me at the manor
she'd find a way
to get this to me.
She really made it happen.
Hmm?
She decided to slip in
some paintings of herself, too.
FILTER APPLIED TO EYES
[YURU] Pain in the neck.
You said you met with Jin?
At a Kagemori place?
Yup. Sorry to say
Asa wasn't there.
Which means...
since she wasn't there,
you must have exchanged
information
about my mom and dad.
[ON TV] You just had to
figure it out so quickly,
didn't you? You damn brat.
[DERA] Yeah, I get it.
So the fake Asa
is a Zashiki-Warashi.
And now she's being held hostage
along with some of the kids
from the village.
Got any idea which ones
they kidnapped?
Don't have a clue.
How many do they have?
[Yuru groans]
[sighs]
And he mentioned me by name?
I'm sure that doesn't feel good,
considering what's at stake.
You'd have to be stupid to just
walk into such an obvious trap.
I'll say. He did manage
to capture the fake Asa,
so we're dealing
with a Daemon Wielder.
We're in a difficult spot here.
[YURU] I vote we let
the bandits go in first.
[DERA] Sounds like they're
itchin' for a fight anyway.
Should be easy to let those
hot heads take the bait for us.
Best case scenario,
we get lucky with the timing.
Maybe we can rescue the kids
while they duke it out.
I suppose we can save her, too,
fake Asa.
But only because it'll help me
to track down Danji.
I'll find them both
and squeeze them for info
on the village.
-They might even know...
-[Right giggles]
...something
about my mom and dad.
Hey, what's the big idea,
laughing at me?
Didn't you say we're probably
dealing with a Daemon Wielder?
That means we should be able
to detect his location
with Left and Right.
We could even trick him,
place you two somewhere,
so he thinks I'm nearby.
[DERA] Yeah, good idea.
We can send them
into warehouse one first
to intercept.
What about us?
Somewhere in range with my bow.
Sure. There's a factory
across from the warehouse.
Comparatively, how tall is it?
The factory's a little higher up
than the warehouse.
-[YURU] That's perfect...
-[KEN] Ms. Hana, what is this?
Don't care.
And if you don't wanna
get dragged into their bullshit,
you shouldn't either.
[RIGHT] Mmm...
I'm a mite loathe to be far
from our master's side.
Do you feel it's safe?
I'll get out of there
if anything dangerous
comes my way.
I'm not planning to be a hero.
I'll be counting on you.
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[birds chirping]
I want to see my brother.
Should we be worried
that she's repeating
the same sentence over and over?
-I want to see my brother.
-[GABBY] Yep, she's broken.
[HAGURE] Well, I guess it's okay
as long as her hands
are still moving.
No, not okay.
All the background
characters are Yuru.
Mm...
STUDIO OUTSIDER
Why don't we take
a little break?
[ALL] Sounds good.
[HAGURE] Would you like
some tea, Tachikawa?
[Tachikawa crying]
Your stories are all so sweet!
I don't know how you do it!
So glad to hear
you like my work! Hooray!
For real, though.
It's kinda crazy you can create
beautiful stuff like that
when you come
from such a bloodthirsty family.
[HAGURE] It's because
my family's so bloodthirsty.
I just drew the idyllic world
I wished I could live in, and...
-folks liked it.
-[NARRATOR] Hikaru Hagure
is a master of heartfelt,
happy manga.
It hurts my soul
to live a life where things
like vengeance, betrayal,
and cold-blooded murder
are basically normal.
Hey, for the record,
I've never killed anyone!
Me neither!
[HAGURE]
Then it's not too late.
You two could quit
and get legitimate jobs.
[HARUO] Yeah, but working here,
I've got a boss
who literally cleans up
my messes if I screw up.
That's hard to beat.
[TACHIKAWA] Plus it pays well,
and I really need the money.
[HAGURE] Hmm...
Fair enough.
I just hate that in our world,
people who could otherwise
have lived ordinary lives
are forced
to bloody their hands.
It's not right.
So here's a solution for you.
Become the clan head
and then you can fire us.
Don't wanna! I'm always
saying I have no desire
to lead this shady family.
Wait, here's an idea.
Why don't you two become
pro manga assistants
and work in my studio instead?
[TACHIKAWA]
I have zero artistic talent.
[HARUO] It's not nice to poach
other people's employees,
you know.
I'm no good with manga stuff,
but if you ever
need anything else,
then just say the word.
My siblings and I'll help.
We owe the Kagemori clan
big time.
[TACHIKAWA] You have siblings?
I didn't know that.
Yep. Natsuki is the eldest.
Then there's Fuyuki.
I'm third in line.
And Akio's the baby.
All the Kuroya siblings
at your service.
[TACHIKAWA] Four of you?
Man, that's a lot.
[HARUO] Yeah.
We're not related by blood,
but we were in the same
care home together, so...
[TACHIKAWA] Sorry.
I get if you don't want
to talk about it.
I was being nosy.
Not at all. It's fine.
We were all abandoned as babies.
Left on the doorstep
of a nursery
run by the Kagemoris.
How could any-bunny not love
such an adorable little face?
Oh, wow.
I had no idea the Kagemoris were
in the childcare business.
We run an orphanage, too.
My dad's a bit of a softie
when it comes to kids.
Just them, though.
[TACHIKAWA] Surely
that's not all there is to it.
I mean, with your family,
there must be
an ulterior motive, right?
I guess so.
I'm sure a lot of our
charitable work is performative,
letting the public see
our good side and all that.
[HARUO] Yeah, look at me
and my siblings.
They took us all in,
and they brought us up
to be foot soldiers
in their evil clan.
[laughing]
[Natsuki sighs]
I want out.
What are you looking at,
Natsuki?
A matchmaking site.
I really want to quit.
Hmm. We've got work.
The master and Jin
are plotting something.
Here. Know the way?
I think so.
What's up? Is Gabby headed out
somewhere?
Yeah. With Natsuki,
Fuyuki, and the master.
Now, listen closely.
This is important.
[AKIO] It's unusual for her
to leave the manor without Asa.
[HARUO]
Asa is currently non-functional.
They're scared she'll screw up,
so they're going without her.
Where to?
[HARUO] Hmm?
The Fujimurayama warehouses.
We got word about a move
against Yuru.
[Yuru exhales]
[YURU] It's the full moon.
And the hour of the Boar
is in about two hours.
Dera's ready.
And Left and Right
are in position.
No sign of the enemy yet.
Are the bandits here?
Could they be lying in wait
somewhere?
[grunts]
[grunts softly]
[growls]
[Yuru grunts]
How? Where did
this thing come from?
I didn't sense anything.
It didn't even make a sound!
[grunting softly]
[growls]
[Yuru exhales]
Dera hasn't noticed it yet.
Neither have Left and Right.
Which means...
it's totally undetectable.
There's no bloodlust.
But one quick twist of my neck,
and I'd be dead
before I could react.
[exhales]
If I called out to them
right now,
who'd be able to help me
out of this the fastest?
Simple. I'm your guardian, kid.
Plus, your cute little sister
told me to watch your back.
[Yuru grunts softly]
[YURU] Guess I'm putting
my faith in you.
Dera, shoot this thing!
[gasps]
[DERA] What is that?
When did it get here?
[Dera gasps]
[Dera gasps, grunts]
[DERA] Yuru!
Where are Left and Right?
[Right growls]
[grunts]
[RIGHT] 'Tis like hitting air.
[grunting]
[yells]
[spits] 'Tis a bit smaller.
Merely a bit.
[RIGHT] Then we'll have
to tear it apart piece by piece.
[LEFT] Not how
I prefer to do battle.
[both grunt]
[Right grunts]
[both gasp]
[RIGHT] They're gone?
Young Yuru! Good evening!
[Yuru grunts softly]
[YURU] Asuma Kagemo...
[groans]
[ASUMA] Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you motion sick?
[Yuru grunts softly]
This thing...
Is it your other daemon?
Indeed! Together,
they are Kin'u-gyokuto.
This one is named Yozakura.
I'm genuinely impressed
by how undetectable they are.
[Asuma giggles]
[YURU] Where's the other?
[ASUMA] You refer to Asagiri.
I'm afraid
they're weak at night,
so they won't be joining us.
Conversely, Yozakura
doesn't like the day,
so they try
to only operate at night.
[YURU] Hmm.
So I could take them
when it's light out. Noted.
[SHINGO]
This brat gives me the creeps.
You're alone in enemy territory.
How are you calm enough
to make small talk?
Better not let him see
my daemons yet.
You idiot.
Go and tell the whole world
about your daemon's weaknesses,
why don't you?
It's a show of good faith.
We would like him to trust us.
If you want my trust,
then answer honestly.
Are you after Seal?
It is as I told you
back at the manor.
I believe those with
special powers should be allowed
to live their lives
under the jurisdiction
of suitable overseers.
Not independently.
[YURU]
The heck is "jurisdiction?"
[ASUMA]
So what do you say, Yuru?
[YURU] Hm?
[Asuma chuckles]
Tell me, would you like to die?
-[running footsteps]
-[panting]
Where is he? In here?
He was kidnapped by that
skull-faced cluster of moths.
Then they vanished here.
What? Are you able
to track Yuru's scent?
[Right groans] I think not.
The tang of blood hangs
too heavy.
'Tis hard to make him out.
[Dera sighs]
[switch flips]
Good evening to you.
[DERA] Twin katanas.
They're daemons. I see.
You're the guy
the shaman mentioned.
The pervert!
[IVAN] Time out.
How is that the reputation
I got from the guy?
Wow, man, that is brutal.
Not like I love the bandits,
but did you have to kill them?
You mean these pests
in the corners,
trying to interrupt our deal?
None of these people had to die
if Yuru had come alone
like I told him to.
And these must be
the Divine Guardians.
Yuru's daemons.
What I don't get is
why the natural enemies
of Break and Seal would form
a contract with a twin?
Especially you, Left.
Your compatibility
with Seal couldn't be worse.
With you around,
Seal might flat out refuse
to form a contract with Yuru.
Hate to say it, but...
to ensure everything works out,
you gotta die.
[scoffs]
The gentleman wants a duel!
-What say you?
-[bone cracks]
I gladly accept.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
[IVAN] To ensure
everything works out,
you gotta die.
[SHINGO] There's no place
for you in Higashi anymore.
[RIGHT] It's Yuru's parents!
I smell the blood
of Mine and Nagisa!
EPISODE 16
KAGEMORI AND SHINGO